Finding Aid for the Stafford Leak Warren Papers LSC.0987
UCLA Library Special Collections
- II. Manhattan Engineering District Papers.
  - Lists of Nagasaki Photographs., September 1945.; 2 items:
    - 1. List of photographs atomic bomb area Nagasaki, Kyushu, Japan photographed by Joseph Calev., September 22, 1945.; (2pp.). (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - 2. Copy list, damage pictures Nagasaki., undated; (2 duplicates, 2pp. each). (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, structural damage, Nagasaki., undated; 62 items. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Photograph, aerial view of Nagasaki, post strike, section 2., undated; 1 item. (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Negatives and Lists, Nagasaki Artifacts., August 1945.; 12 items:
    - 1-4. Negatives in envelope marked Extra Negatives., undated; (4 items including envelope). (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - 5-8. Negatives in envelope marked Use These for Prints., undated; (4 items including envelope). (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - 9-11. Photographs produced from negatives, assorted artifacts from Nagasaki Hospital and Medical School post strike., undated; (3 photographs). (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - 12. List of artifacts from Hospital and Medical School in Nagasaki taken in September-October 1945., August 9, 1945.; (3pp.). (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Notes and Graphs, Hiroshima and Nagasaki., 3 items:
    - 1. Notes, excerpts from Penny Report., undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - 2. Graph, miles, planes, and ships., undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - 3. Graph, PSI/Ft., Nagasaki and Hiroshima., undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Report with photographs and charts, vol.1, Nagasaki, Atomic Bomb Damage, (205pp. including cover), by Walter C. Youngs, Jr., Maj. Corps of Engineers., August 9, 1945, March 1946.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Report with photographs and charts, vol.2, Nagasaki Atomic Bomb Damage, (213pp. including cover), by Walter C. Youngs, Jr., Maj. Corps of Engineers., August 9, 1945, March 1946.; 1 item. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Reports and Patient Charts, Effects of Bomb., 1946.; 10 items:
    - 1. Report with charts, Influence of Radioactivity upon Sperm of Atomic Bomb Patients, by Dr. Koichi Ishikawa., September 8, 1946.; (3pp. total). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 2. Report, Influence (Good Influence?) on the Feminine Sexual Organ by the Atomic Bombing at Hiroshima, no.1, by K. Nagata, Hiroshima Red Cross Hospital., September 1, 1946.; (6pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 3. Report, Influence (Good Influence?) on the Feminine Sexual Organ by the Atomic Bombing at Hiroshima, no.2, by K. Nagata, Hiroshima Red Cross Hospital., September 1, 1946.; (3pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 4. Report, Influence (Bad Influence?) on the Feminine Sexual Organ by the Atomic Bombing at Hiroshima, by K. Nagata, Hiroshima Red Cross Hospital., September 1, 1946.; (4pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 5. Report, General Statistics, by Dr. Ito, dermatologist, Hiroshima Red Cross Hospital., undated; (11pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 6. Notes on patients, by Dr. Fumio Shigeto, Assistant Director Red Cross Hospital, Uzina., undated; (2pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 7. Note, GI tract of atomic bomb patients, to Colonel LeRoy., undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 8. Rough report, statistics of atomic bomb victims at Hiroshima by Dr. Akiyama., undated; (6pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 9. Copy report, The 3rd Report of the Influence of the Atomic Bomb Explosion on the Ear, Nose, and Throat by Teiichi Kashiwado., undated; (2pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 10. Copy report, The Attitude of the Eosinophile cells in Blood and Bone Marrow of the Atomic Bomb Patients at Nagasaki, in the 3rd and 4th Month after the Explosion, by Drs. Hideo Ueda and Soshiro Nikaido., January 11, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Patient Data, Effects of Atomic Bomb., 1946.; 215 items:
    - 1-142. Patient data in envelope marked, Data Collected on Persons at Home of Dr. Nagai., undated; (142 items including envelope). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 143. Table X, Differential White Counts of Inhabitants of Nishiyama Area, by Dr. Ishikawa., undated; (2pp.). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 144-152. Chart of Nagasaki Patients., August 1946.; (9pp.). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 153-185. Patient data., August 21, 1946.; (33pp.). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 186-206. Patient data., August 23, 1946.; (21pp.). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 207-215. Patient data., undated; (9pp.). (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Patient Data and Reports, Effects of Atomic Bomb., 1946.; 20 items:
    - 1-18. Patient data, Nagasaki Medical School., August 24, 1946.; (18pp.). (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - 19. Copy report, The Influence of the Radioactivity upon the Inhabitants of Nishiyama District, Nagasaki, 2nd report, by Dr. Kazuo Ishikawa., undated; (57pp.). (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - 20. Copy report, Preliminary Report of the Damage on Structures Due to the Atomic Bomb, by Yasuo Kondo, Professor in Civil Engineering Department, Kyoto Imperial University., undated; (3pp.). (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Reports on Atomic Bombing of Japan., 1946.; 2 items:
    - 1. Copy report, The Atomic Bomb, by Dr. Yoshio Nishina., undated; (10pp.). (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - 2. Copy report, Japanese Atomic Bomb Conference, Special Committee for Research and Investigation of the Damage Done by the Atomic Bombings., November 30, 1945.; (35pp.). (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Report, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey., 1946.; 2 items:
    - 1. Copy report, The United States Strategic Bombing Survey: The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Chairman's Office., June 19, 1946.; (26pp. including cover). (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - 2. Publication, The United States Strategic Bombing Survey: The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, with maps, Chairman's Office., June 30, 1946.; (30pp. total, including cover). (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Copy report, section B, Radiation in Hiroshima and Nagasaki, with Appendices A, B, and C (145 pp. including cover), by Captain Richard A. Tybout, Corps of Engineers., April 6, 1946.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Japanese FM Study Charts With Translation Notes., 8 items:
    - 1. #5., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 2. #6., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 3. #7., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 4. #9., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 5. #10., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 6. #11., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 7. #12., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 8. #13., (6 duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Photographs with notes, Hiroshima and Nagasaki victims., undated; 17 items. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Letters and Reports, Hiroshima and Nagasaki., 1947.; 4 items:
    - 1. Letter, James F. Nolan, M.D. to Robert J. Buettner., October 29, 1947.; (3pp.). (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 2. Letter Joe W. Howland, M.D. to Robert J. Buettner., November 5, 1947.; (3pp.). (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 3. Report with cover letter, B.M. Brundage, M.D. to SLW., November 12, 1947.; (6pp. including cover letter, plus duplicate p. 4). (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 4. Report with cover letter, A Brief Account of Observations in Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Melvin A. Block to Robert J. Buettner., November 16, 1947.; (5pp. including cover letter). (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Report and Memos, Hiroshima Radiation., 1952-1953.; 5 items:
    - 1. Index card, File 13., undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 2. Copy report, Residual Radioactivity and Radiation Signs and Symptoms in Hiroshima, by L.A. Woodbury., undated; (11pp.). (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 3. Copy memo, Dr. J. McDonald to Dr. Taylor, Dr. Reynolds., July 14, 1952. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 4. Copy memo, Dr. Takeshima, Dr. Tamagaki to Dr. Taylor., April 8, 1953.; (3pp.). (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 5. Copy memo, Dr. Tamagaki (reported by D.J. McDonald) to Research Committee., October 3, 1953.; (4pp.). (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Report, Medical Effects of Atomic Bomb., 3 items:
    - 1. Index card File 28., undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 2. Report with graphs, A Summary of the Medical Effects of the Atomic Bomb upon Inhabitants of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, by the Medical Section of Manhattan Engineering District, Douglas L. Wake, Captain, and Melvin A. Block, Lieutenant., undated; (23pp. total). (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 3. Rough report with graphs, A summary of the medical effects of the atomic bomb upon inhabitants of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, by the Medical Section of the Manhattan Engineering District, Douglas L. Wake, Captain, and Melvin A. Block, Lieutenant., undated; (43pp. total plus duplicates). (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Letters, and Notes. Medical Aspects of Nuclear Energy., 1948-1971.; 9 items:
    - 1. Index card, File #15., undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 2. Copy disposition form, FCWD-D (Captain George Prassinos) to FCJ2 (Att: Mr. Fred Winsted)., December 9, 1970. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 3. Publication cover, Medical Aspects of Nuclear Energy, Armed Forces Special Weapons Project National Military Establishment., 1949. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 4. Copy report, Medical Report of the Joint Commission for the Investigation of the Effects of the Atomic Bomb in Japan, by Oughterson, LeRoy, Liebow, Hammond, Barnett, Rosenbaum, and Schneider, The Army Institute of Pathology, The Office of the Air Surgeon, Washington D.C.., undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 5. Letter, Gavin Hadden to SLW., March 11, 1948.; (4pp.). (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 6. Copy address by Dr. Nishina., undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 7. Note, DB to SLW., May 10, 1971. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 8. Note, Look for Hiroshima Physical Damage Volume, [to SLW]., undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 9. Letter, I.A. Warheit to SLW., January 26, 1949. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Letters and Reports, Manhattan Project., 1946.; 3 items:
    - 1. Copy letter [report], Comments on Manhattan Project,, SLW to Colonel McCrae., January 3, 1946.; (28pp.). (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - 2. Copy cover letter for Dr. Wilson's report, SLW to General Groves., January 16, 1946. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - 3. Copy report, Detailed Questions Relating to Inspection as a Technical Problem, by Dr. Carroll Wilson., undated; (18pp.). (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Contents of binder labelled, Copies of Translated Japanese Reports, Re: Medical Effects of the Atomic Bombs at Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Book I, (502 pp., including cover), by Tokyo, Kyushu, Kyoto, and Osaka Imperial Universities and Nagasaki Medical College., December 1945.; 1 item. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Translated Japanese Reports, Medical Effects of Atomic Bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki., December 1945.; 2 items:
    - 1. Index card, File #35., undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - 2. Contents of binder labeled, Copies of Translated Japanese Reports, Re: Medical Effects of the Atomic Bombs at Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Book IV, by Tokyo, Kyushu, Kyoto, and Osaka Imperial Universities and Nagasaki Medical College., December 1945.; (399pp., including cover). (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Copy report, Report on the Medical Studies of the Effects of the Atomic Bomb, (3 duplicates, 69 pp. each), by Dr. Masao Tsuzuki, Professor of the Tokyo Imperial University., February 28, 1946.; 1 item. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Copy report, Collected Information regarding Medical Findings at Hiroshima and Nagasaki One Year after the Atomic Bombings, (5 duplicates, 152pp. each), by Colonel James P. Cooney, Captain Douglas L. Wake, and 1st Lieutenant Melvin A. Block, of the Medical Section, Manhattan District., August-September 1946.; 1 item. (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Atomic Bomb Effects on Human Reproduction., 1946.; 2 items:
    - 1. Copy report, Atomic Bomb Influence upon Human Sperm,, by Kentaro Siniz, Assistant Professor of the First Surgical Department, Tokyo Imperial University., December 6, 1945.; (3pp.). (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - 2. Copy report, The Influence of the Atomic Bomb upon the Functions of the Female Genital Organs,, by S. Mitani, M. Ito, S. Nozu, Y. Tumuji, T. Kaseki, T. Iwai, M. Iwatate, M. Watanabe, from the Gynecological Clinic of the Tokyo Imperial University., July 15, 1946.; (8pp.). (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Reports, Atomic Energy., 1945.; 4 items:
    - 1. Copy report, Senate Bill S. 1717, for the Development and Control of Atomic Energy, introduced by Mr. McMahon., December 20, 1945.; (13pp.). (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 2. Copy report, Aide Memoire, the Canadian Ambassador to the Secretary of State., November 30, 1945.; (4pp.). (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 3. Copy report, Questions Having a Bearing on the Future Activities of the Working Group, notes by SLW., December 27, 1945.; (17pp.). (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 4. Copy press statement by Secretary of War concerning May-Johnson Atomic Energy Bill H.R.4566., November 14, [no year].; (3pp.). (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Reports, Atomic Bomb Control., 1945.; 6 items:
    - 1. Copy report, Text of Atomic Bomb Plan., November 15, 1945.; (3pp.). (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 2. Copy report, Text of Byrnes' Talk on Atomic Bomb Control., November 16, 1945.; (7pp.). (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 3. Copy excerpts from the Secretary's press conference., November 21, 1945. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 4. Copy report, Truman's Message to Congress on Atomic Bomb., undated; (4pp.). (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 5. Copy report, President's press conference., November 20, 1945.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 6. Copy report, Text of President's Navy Day Speech in Central Park on the Aims of U.S. Foreign Policy., undated; (7pp.). (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Legislation for Development and Control of Atomic Energy., 1945.; 4 items:
    - 1. Copy report, Senate Bill S.1717, for the Development and Control of Atomic Energy, introduced by Mr. McMahon., December 20, 1945.; (14pp.). (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 2. Copy report, Senate Bill S.1463, for the Development and Control of Atomic Energy, introduced by Mr. Johnson., October 3, 1945.; (14pp.). (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 3. Copy report, House Bill H.R.4566, for the Development and Control of Atomic Energy, introduced by Mr. May., (16pp.). (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 4. Copy note, for Sect. 4 (Advisory Boards)., undated; (3 duplicates). (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Copy Symposium on Atomic Energy and its Implications (50pp.), American Philosophical Society and National Academy of Sciences., November 16-17, 1945.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Clippings, and Photographs, Atomic Energy., 1945-1967.; 9 items:
    - 1. Copy telegram, G.W. Hendren, M.D. to SLW., February 9, 1945. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 2. Copy cable, Christopher T. Boland to SLW., February 9, 1945.; (2 duplicates). (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 3. Note, R.J. Brackett to SLW., February 22, 1945. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 4. Blank trip pass., undated; (2 items). (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 5. Letter, Dr. Masao Tsuzuki to SLW., August 24, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 6. Letter, Douglas Wake, Captain M.C. to SLW., September 24, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 7. Newsclippings, atomic bomb films; peace-time development of atomic energy., May 17, 1967, August 2, 1946.; (2 items). (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 8. Copy letter, I.A. Warheit to SLW., January 26, 1949.; (2 duplicates). (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 9. Photographs, atomic bomb destruction., undated; (3 items). (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Letters and Memos., 1946.; 10 items:
    - 1. Letter, John J. Flick, M.D. to SLW., September 24, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 2. Copy routing sheet., undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 3. Letter, John J. Flick, M.D. to SLW., November 29, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 4. Copy memo, Robert J. Buettner to Dr. A.H. Dowdy., November 21, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 5. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to John J. Flick, M.D.., December 3, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 6. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to John J. Flick, M.D.., December 9, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 7. Letter, John J. Flick, M.D. to Robert J. Buettner., December 12, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 8. Letter, John J. Flick, M.D. to SLW., November 14, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 9. Memo, C.M. Jarvis to Robert J. Buettner., December 19, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 10. Copy memo, Robert J. Buettner to C.M. Jarvis., December 20, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Letters and Reports, Japanese Bombings., 1945-1952.; 7 items:
    - 1. Copy letter, W.A. Parish, Jr. to Dr. Philip Morrison., February 6, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 2. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner, to Dr. Douglas L. Wake., October 21, 1947. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 3. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Dr. Melvin A. Block., October 21, 1947. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 4. Copy Letter, Robert J. Buettner to Dr. Joseph Nolan., October 22, 1947. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 5. Letter, Merril Eisenbud to Robert J. Buettner., September 4, 1952. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 6. Copy memo, SLW to Major General, L.R. Groves., November 27, 1945. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 7. Copy report, Preliminary Report of Findings of Atomic Bomb Investigating Groups at Hiroshima and Nagasaki., 1945.; (38pp.). (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Reports, and Memos, the Atomic Bomb., 1946-1948.; 14 items:
    - 1. Copy cover letter, SLW to Dr. Herbert Scoville., January 31, 1947. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 2. Copy report, Types of Injury Caused by Atomic Bomb Detonation in Hiroshima and Nagasaki, by SLW and Major J. Howland., undated; (4pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 3. Copy memo, Lauris Norstad; L.R. Groves to the Surgeon General., July 26, 1946, August 30, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 4. Copy memo, William S. Stone, Colonel to Commanding General, Manhattan Engineering District., July 26, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 5. Copy memo, L.R. Groves to the Surgeon General., August 7, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 6. Copy memo, William S. Stone to Commanding General, Manhattan Project., August 15, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 7. Copy letter, Lewis H. Weed, M.D. to Major General Norman T. Kirk., June 28, 1946.; (2pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 8. Copy list, Attendance at Meeting of the Committee on Atomic Casualties., June 24, 1946. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 9. Copy report, Measurement of the Residual Radiation Intensity at the Hiroshima and Nagasaki Atomic Bomb Sites, by Nello Pace and Robert E. Smith., April 16, 1946.; (17pp. including cover). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 10. Negative copy letter, Walter J. Johnson, President Academic Press, Incorporated to SLW., August 15, 1946.; (2 duplicates). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 11. Note, Instructions for Keyboard., undated (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 12. Copy reprint, The Effects of the Atomic Bomb Irradiation on the Japanese, by Joe W. Howland and SLW, received., January 13, 1948.; (6pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 13. Copy report, Effects of the Atomic Bomb Irradiation on Japanese, by Joe W. Howland and SLW, received., January 13, 1948.; (27pp.). (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 14. Copy letter, Robert J. Buettner to Dr. Joe Howland., June 27, 1947. (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Senate Proceedings., January 22, 1946.; 2 items:
    - 1. Copy report, U.S. Senate, Report of Proceedings, Hearing Held before Special Committee on Atomic Energy, S.1717, vol.1, Ward and Paul Electreporter, Incorporated., January 22, 1946.; (97pp. including cover). (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - 2. Copy report, U.S. Senate, Report of Proceedings, Hearing Held before Special Committee on Atomic Energy, S. 1717, 1463, 1557, vol.2., January 23, 1946.; (72pp. including cover). (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Copy report, Personnel of Oak Ridge Hospital and Clinic, (114pp.), edited by Major Frank L. Bryant., October 1, 1945.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Copy report, Lecture Series on Nuclear Physics, (341pp.), E.M. McMillan, Lecturer., October 5, 1943.; 1 item. (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Motion Picture Films of Atomic Bombing, Japan., 1945.; 12 16mm. reels:
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Digital reproductions of these materials are available for viewing in the Library Special Collections reading room.
    - Hiroshima, physical damage., 1945 September 21-October 10; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:10:01) (Box 69, Reel 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Part of "Effects of the Atomic Bomb on Hiroshima and Nagasaki"
    - Hiroshima, physical damage., 1945 September 21-October 10; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:08:17) (Box 69, Reel 2)
    - Radioactivity., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:08:03) (Box 69)
    - Radioactivity., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:07:36) (Box 69, Reel 4)
    - Shadow and heat., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:11:36) (Box 69, Reel 5)
    - Biological studies at Hiroshima, 1945 September 25-October 2; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:06:40) (Box 69, Reel 6)
    - Effects on the human body., 1945 October 1-20; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:09:35) (Box 69, Reel 7)
    - Radiation sickness and pathology., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:08:59) (Box 69, Reel 8)
    - Principal hospital and first aid stations., 1945 October 1-20; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:11:46) (Box 69, Reel 9)
    - Nagasaki, physical damage., 1945 September 24-1946 January 25; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:08:28) (Box 69, Reel 10)
    - Nagasaki, physical damage., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:10:06) (Box 69, Reel 11)
    - Nagasaki, physical damage., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:10:20) (Box 69, Reel 12)
    - Shadow., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:05:42) (Box 69, Reel 13)
      Part of "Physical Science Report on Nagasaki"
  - Motion Picture Films of Atomic Bombing, Japan, and Related Material., 1945.; Glass slides and 10 reels 16 mm. film:
    - Heat., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:09:24) (Box 70, Reel 14)
    - Blast., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:10:11) (Box 70, Reel 15)
    - Radioactivity., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:10:18) (Box 70, Reel 16)
    - Effects on the human body., 1945 September 24-25; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:06:36) (Box 70, Reel 17)
    - Biological studies., 1945 October 12-17; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:08:09) (Box 70, Reel 18)
    - Biological studies and epilogue., 1945; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; 0:06:04) (Box 70, Reel 19)
  - Issues of the Oakridge Journal. (Box 71, Box 72)
    See also oversize package 3 below.
- III. Operation Crossroads Papers.
  (See also Section 4 and oversize packages 4, 5 and 12 below.
  - SLW's notebook., August 1946.; 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - SLW's notebook., October 1946.; 1 item. (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Notes and Letters., 1945-46.; 16 items:
    - 1. List, selected file numbers., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 2. List, telephone numbers., December 1, 1945. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 3. Note, messages for SLW., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 4. Copy telegram, R.S. Stone, M.D., to SLW., January 28, 1946. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 5. Note, Mrs. Coolidge to SLW., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 6. Letter, E. Forrest Merrill to SLW., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 7-9. Rough notes., undated; (3 items). (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 10-14. Voucher with memoranda of payment., October 1946.; (5 items). (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 15. Postcard, Guy to SLW., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 16. Clipping, veteran from Bikini, New York Tribune., 1946. (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Notes and Letters., 1965, 1969; 7 items:
    - 1. Copy letter, Ruth G. Van Cleve to Edwin G. Bowen., January 22, 1969. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - 2. Copy news release by Milner, Dept. of the Interior., January 18, 1969.; (10pp.). (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - 3. Clipping, radioactive fallout, Washington Post., November 3, 1965. (Box 73, Folder 4)